Pasquale Pio Francavilla

Product Owner

Zug, ZG 6300 pasfranc@gmail.com +41766827980

Motivated and forward-thinking agile scrum product owner with 3+ years experience in business and technical leading roles. Eager to mentor and support teams with leadership and guidance over a wide range of product development efforts. In this role, I was able to coordinate 90% of product completion in line with the company roadmap.

Work Experience

Payment Product Owner

Dodax AG / myWorld Operations - Zug / remote January 2020 to Present

- Completed 90% of the delineated product road map through the product backlog prioritization, user stories definition, and business analysis requirements through continuous negotiation between internal and external stakeholders.
- Reduced frauds in payments by 95% identifying fraud patterns, enforced 3D secure payments, tuned payment service providers rules to meet liability acceptance.
- Increased number of sales in Switzerland +15% in last three months through market research about trending payment methods and best-fit payment provider and customer feedback.
- Reduced customer service ticket creation -10% discovering the common error patterns and improving automated error messages on the checkout payment method screen.
- Increased checkout conversion rate up to 83% investigating and removing failure path, implementing A/B testing.
- Released a new version of the website UX/UI at the beginning of 2021 with zero downtime.
- Coordinated the implementation of a third-party marketplace payment solution with more than 200 third parties sellers and processed 1 million transactions. The solution was including KYC, splitting payments into wallets, dispute management, settlement reporting system, payment subscription.
- Managed the payment and e-commerce core agile scrum team up to 5 developers remotely located across Europe.
- Facilitated several cross-functional scrum feature teams of up to 10 developers, architects, leads.
- Guided and cooperated with the other areas of product owners to successfully end-to-end release of more than 15 new features in last year.
- Direct reported reports, results, and business analysis to the CEO.

Team Leader Senior Software Engineer

Dodax AG - Zug / remote March 2017 to December 2019

- Built from scratch a new payment orchestration system, with the possibility to enable and disable payment methods based on country, basket amount, customers' credit check.
- Defined best practice guidelines and implementation of the original version of the internal frontend application used as a template for further internal admin applications.

- Implemented Authentication and authorization client system used in more than 5 internal applications.
- Integrated more than 10 payment methods in 12 countries with 4 different payment service providers for the new Dodax website launch in 2018.
- Led the payment and e-commerce team up to 5 developers remotely located across Europe.

J2EE Spring/AngularJs Developer

Cornèr Bank (Consultant) - Lugano, TI November 2015 to February 2017

- Implemented Full-stack (Spring/AngularJs), tested and maintained J2EE applications for Cornèr bank partners management. Back-end and REST API tested (Spring/Camel) for the mobile Cornèr Bank App.
- Offered Front-end consultancy for Backbase widgets development.
- Gained experience using IBM products like DB2, Websphere, and RAD.

Groovy/AngularJs Developer

PlacesToShine sagl (adbee.com - startup) - Lugano, Tl May 2015 to November 2015

- Accomplished additional features to existing applications, test, and maintenance of J2EE applications using Grails (Groovy, Spring, Hibernate) framework and front-end for the Adbee shop using the AngularJs framework.
- Finalized experience on Google Maps API, MongoDB, and the GGTS Eclipse IDE.

J2EE Developer

Engineering Ingegneria Informatica (Consultant) - Assago, Lombardia May 2013 to April 2015

- Developed additional features for existing applications, test and maintenance of J2EE applications for the management of pension funds (Intesa Sanpaolo Bank) using Struts and Hibernate, jQuery, and jQuery UI frameworks.
- Analyzed, and developed J2EE applications using Spring framework and Hibernate.
- Integrated enterprise applications with third-party and CICS services.
- Report development of 40+ bank document templates using Birt Engine.
- Experienced writing queries in IBM DB2 and CICS environments.
- Good knowledge of the Eclipse IDE and the Tomcat Web Container and Jboss.

Java Developer

Svimservice (Exprivia Group) - Molfetta, Puglia January 2012 to May 2013

- Designed high-quality and policy-compliant solutions for Public Administration healthcare software for Apulia Region using J2EE, Spring MVC framework, and Hibernate.
- Produced more than 100 document reports using Crystal Report 2008 and Oracle SQL.
- Web Application Analysis and testing using Selenium.
- Troubleshot and fixed issues/defects resulting from tests.
- Elaborated excellent design and development documentation.

Education

Master's Degree in Computer Science

University of Salerno - Salerno, Campania

Skills

 Jira, Scrum Agile, A/B Testing, Team Leadership, Confluence, Project management, AWS, Docker containers, Rancher, Terraform, Java, Spring Boot, Struts, Hibernate, IBM DB2, Sql Server, Oracle SQL, Tomcat, Eclipse, Bootstrap, Grails, AWS, Docker, Microservice Architecture, MariaDB, Kubernetes, Selenium Tests, Regression Test

Languages

- English Fluent
- German Beginner